I'd like to talk to you today
أريد أن أتحدث معكم اليوم
about a whole new way to think about sexual activity
عن طريقة جديدة كلياً في التفكير حول النشاط الجنسي
and sexuality education, by comparison.
و التثقيف الجنسي, على سبيل المقارنة
If you talk to someone today in America
لو تكلمتَ اليوم مع شخص في أميريكا
about sexual activity,
عن النشاط الجنسي,
you'll find pretty soon you're not just talking
ستكتشف قريباً أنك لم تعد تتحدث
about sexual activity.
فقط عن النشاط الجنسي.
You're also talking about baseball.
ولكن أيضاً عن كرة البيسبول.
Because baseball is the dominant cultural metaphor
لأن كرة البيسبول هي التعبير و التشبيه الأكثر استخداماً عند ثقافة
that Americans use to think about
الأمريكيين والذين يستخدمونه ليفكّروا
and talk about sexual activity,
ويتحدثوا عن النشاط الجنسي.
and we know that because there's
ونحن نعلم ذلك بسبب وجود
all this language in English
كل تلك التعابير في اللغة الإنكليزية
that seems to be talking about baseball
والتي تبدو وكأنها تتحدث عن كرة البيسبول
but that's really talking about sexual activity.
ولكنها في الحقيقة تتحدث عن النشاط الجنسي.
So, for example, you can be a pitcher or a catcher,
وكمثال, إن كنت الرامي للكرة أو المتلقي,
and that corresponds to whether you
هذا سيشير إلى كونك
perform a sexual act or receive a sexual act.
الفاعل في النشاط الجنسي أو المتلقي لهذا الفعل.
Of course, there are the bases,
طبعاً, هناك قواعد,
which refer to specific sexual activities
والتي تشير إلى نشاطات جنسية معينة
that happen in a very specific order,
تحدث وفق ترتيب معين,
ultimately resulting in scoring a run
والتي سينتج عنها في النهاية تسجيل ركضة كاملة
or hitting a home run,
أو العودة إلى القاعدة بأمان,
which is usually having vaginal intercourse
والتي تعني في العادة حصول اتصال جنسي مهبلي
to the point of orgasm,
والوصول إلى اللذة,
at least for the guy.
عند الشاب عالأقل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You can strike out, which means
إن خرجت من المباراة, هذا يعني
you don't get to have any sexual activity.
لا يمكنك فعل أي نشاط جنسي.
And if you're a benchwarmer,
وإن كنت تجلس كبديل أو احتياط,
you might be a virgin or somebody who for
فأنت عذراء أو شخص
whatever reason isn't in the game,
لأي سبب من الأسباب ليس داخل اللعبة,
maybe because of your age or because of your ability
بسبب عمرك أو قدراتك
or because of your skillset.
أو بسبب مهارتك.
A bat's a penis,
المضرب هوه القضيب,
and a nappy dugout is a vulva, or a vagina.
مكان الجلوس والإنتظار هوه الفرج أو المهبل.
A glove or a catcher's mitt is a condom.
القفاز هو الواقي.
A switch-hitter is a bisexual person,
الذي يضرب بكلتا يديه فهوه ثنائي جنسي,
and we gay and lesbian folks play for the other team.
ونحن المثليون نلعب عند الفريق الآخر.
And then there's this one:
ثم هناك :
"if there's grass on the field, play ball."
"إن وُجِدَ عشب في أرض الملعب, فلنلعب بالكرة"
And that usually refers to
وهذا عادة يعني
if a young person, specifically often a young woman,
إن كان شخص صغير بالسن, وخصيصاً إمرأة صغيرة,
is old enough to have pubic hair,
قد بلغت لدرجة أنه ظهر شعر العانة لديها ,
she's old enough to have sex with.
فهي بالغة لكي تمارس الجنس.
This baseball model is incredibly problematic.
نموذج كرة البيسبول هذا يثير الكثير من المشاكل.
It's sexist. It's heterosexist.
إنه متحيّز جنسياً, ومتحيز للمغايرين جنسياً.
It's competitive. It's goal-directed.
تنافسيّ, و محدد بهدف.
And it can't result in healthy sexuality
ولا يمكن أن ينتج بأي ثقافة جنسية سليمة
developing in young people or in adults.
تتطور عند الشباب أو البالغين.
So we need a new model.
لذلك نحتاج إلى نموذج جديد
I'm here today to offer you that new model.
وأنا هنا اليوم لأقدم لكم هذا النموذج الجديد
And it's based on
وأساسهُ :
pizza.
البيتزا.
Now pizza is something that is universally understood
البيتزا هي شيئ مفهوم عالمياً
and that most people associate with a positive experience.
ومعظم الأشخاص يربطونها بلحظات إيجابية.
So let's do this.
فلنفعل ذلك.
Let's take baseball and pizza and compare it
لنأخذ كرة البيسبول والبيتزا ولنقارنهما
when talking about three aspects of sexual activity:
خلال الحديث عن ثلاث نواحي للنشاط الجنسي :
the trigger for sexual activity,
شرارة النشاط الجنسي,
what happens during sexual activity,
مالذي يحدث خلال هذا النشاط الجنسي,
and the expected outcome of sexual activity.
والنتيجة المتوقعة للنشاط الجنسي.
So when do you play baseball?
إذاً متى تلعب كرة البيسبول ؟
You play baseball when it's baseball season
تلعب البيسبول عند قدوم موسم المباريات
and when there's a game on the schedule.
وعندما يكون هناك مباراة متاحة في جدول المباريات.
It's not exactly your choice.
إن الأمر لا يعود لك بالتحديد
So if it's prom night or a wedding night
إن كان حفل التخرج أو ليلة الزفاف
or at a party or if our parents aren't home,
أو في حفلة أو إن كان أهلنا خارج المنزل,
hey, it's just batter up.
إنه دور اللاعب التالي !
Can you imagine saying to your coach,
هل تتخيل أن تقول لمدربك,
"Uh, I'm not really feeling it today,
"آمم, مزاجي ليس مناسباً للعب اليوم,
I think I'll sit this game out."
لا أعتقد أني سأشارك في اللعب."
That's just not the way it happens.
لا تجري الأمور على هذا النحو .
And when you get together to play baseball,
وعندما تجتمعون للعب البيسبول,
one playing offense, one playing defense,
الأول يلعب هجوم , والثاني دفاع,
somebody's trying to move deeper into the field.
أحدهم يحاول التقدم إلى الوسط الملعب.
That's usually a sign to the boy.
هذه غالباً إشارة إلى الشاب.
Somebody's trying to defend people moving into the field.
وأحد يحاول أن يمنع الآخرين من التقدم إلى وسط الملعب.
That's often given to the girl.
وهذه غالباً إشارة إلى الفتاة.
It's competitive.
إنها منافَسة !
We're not playing with each other.
حيث لا نلعب مع بعضنا.
We're playing against each other.
وإنما ضد بعضنا.
And when you show up to play baseball,
وعندما تأتي للعب كرة البيسبول,
nobody needs to talk about what we're going to do
لن يحتاج أحد أن يذكر مالذي علينا فعله
or how this baseball game might be good for us.
أو بماذا ستفيدنا هذه اللعبة.
Everybody knows the rules.
يعلم الجميع قوانين اللعبة.
You just take your position and play the game.
ستأخذ موقعك وتبدأ اللعب.
But when do you have pizza?
ولكن متى نأكل البيتزا ؟
Well, you have pizza when you're hungry for pizza.
حسن, ستأكل البيتزا عندما تشتهي البيتزا.
It starts with an internal sense, an internal desire, or a need.
حيث تبدأ بإحساس داخلي, رغبة داخلية, أو حاجة.
"Huh. I could go for some pizza."
" هاه, أعتقد أنني أرغب بالبيتزا. "
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And because it's an internal desire,
ولأنه إحساس داخلي,
we actually have some sense of control over that.
فلدينا في الحقيقة نوع من التحكم به.
I could decide that I'm hungry
أستطيع تقرير أنني جائع
but know that it's not a great time to eat.
ولكني أعرف أنه ليس الوقت المناسب للأكل.
And then when we get together with someone for pizza,
وعندما نجتمع مع أشخاص لنأكل البيتزا,
we're not competing with them,
فلن نكون بمنافسةٍ معهم,
we're looking for an experience
سنكون باحثين عن تجربة
that both of us will share
كلانا سيقوم بمشاركتها
that's satisfying for both of us,
وستكون مُرضية لنا ,
and when you get together for pizza with somebody,
وعندما تجتمع مع شخص لأكل البيتزا,
what's the first thing you do?
ما أول أمر ستفعله ؟
You talk about it.
ستتحدث عنها.
You talk about what you want.
ستتحدث عن الذي تريده.
You talk about what you like.
ستتحدث عن الذي تحبه.
You may even negotiate it.
حتى أنه يمكن أن تتفاوض عليه.
"How do you feel about pepperoni?" (Laughter)
"ما رأيك بالبيببروني؟ " (ضحك)
"Not so much, I'm kind of a mushroom guy myself."
"لا أحبها كثيرا, إني من محبّي الفطر "
"Well, maybe we can go half and half."
"حسن, لما لا نأخذها نصف بنصف. "
And even if you've had pizza with somebody
وحتى إن كنت تأكل البيتزا مع نفس الشخص
for a very long time,
لوقت طويل جداً,
don't you still say things like,
ستظل تسأل أشياء مثل ,
"Should we get the usual?"
" كالعادة ؟ "
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Or maybe something a little more adventurous?"
"أو نجرب شيئاً أكثر جرءة ؟ "
Okay, so when you're playing baseball,
حسن, عندما تلعب البيسبول,
so if we talk about during sexual activity,
الآان أثناء النشاط الجنسي,
when you're playing baseball,
عندما تلعب البيسبول,
you're just supposed to round the bases
عليك أن تمرّ على كل القواعد
in the proper order one at a time.
بترتيب مناسب, الواحدة تلو الأخرى.
You can't hit the ball and run to right field.
لا يمكن أن تضرب الكرة وتركض إلى الحقل اليميني.
That doesn't work.
لا تجري اللعبة هكذا.
And you also can't get to second base and say,
وأيضاً لا يمكنك الوصول للقاعدة الثانية وقول ,
"I like it here. I'm going to stay here."
"يعجبني المكان هنا. سأظل واقفاً هنا."
No.
لا.
And also, of course, with baseball, there's, like,
وأيضاً, بالطبع, في البيسبول, هناك
the specific equipment and a specific skill set.
معدّات محددة و مهارات محددة.
Not everybody can play baseball. It's pretty exclusive.
لا يمكن للجميع لعب البيسبول, أنها رياضة خاصة جداً.
Okay, but what about pizza?
حسن ولكن ماذا عن البيتزا؟
When we're trying to figure out what's good for pizza,
عندما نحاول أن نختار نوع البيتزا الأفضل,
isn't it all about what's our pleasure?
أليس هذا يعتمد على ملذتنا الخاصة ؟
There are a million different kinds of pizza.
هناك مليون نوع للبيتزا.
There's a million different toppings.
وهناك ملايين الأشكال المختلفة للصلصة.
There's a million different ways to eat pizza.
وهناك مليون طريقة لأكل البيتزا.
And none of them are wrong. They're different.
ولا واحدة منها خاطئة. وإنما مختلفة عن بعضها .
And in this case, difference is good,
وبهذا الأمر, الإختلاف أمر جيد,
because that's going to increase the chance
لأننا سنزيد فرصة
that we're having a satisfying experience.
أن نقوم بتجربة مُرضية .
And lastly, what's the expected outcome of baseball?
وأخيراً, ماهي النتيجة المتوقعة من مباراة البيسبول ؟
Well, in baseball, you play to win.
في المباراة, تلعب لتربح.
You score as many runs as you can.
تريد أن تحقق أعلى النقاط.
There's always a winner in baseball,
هناك دائماً رابح في البيسبول,
and that means there's always a loser in baseball.
وهذا يعني أن هناك دائماً خاسر في البيسبول.
But what about pizza?
ولكن ماذا عن البيتزا؟
Well, in pizza, we're not really --
في البيتزا, لسنا ....
there's no winning. How do you win pizza?
ليس هناك ربح. كيف ستربح في البيتزا ؟
You don't. But you do look for,
لا يمكنك ذلك, ولكنك ستسأل :
"Are we satisfied?"
"هل كان هذا مُرضياً لنا؟ "
And sometimes that can be different amounts
وأحياناً يمكن لهذا أن يختلف بدرجات
over different times or with different people
حسب أوقات مختلفة أو مع أشخاص مختلفين
or on different days.
أو حسب أيام مختلفة.
And we get to decide when we feel satisfied.
ونحن يمكننا تقرير متى سنشعر بالرضى.
If we're still hungry, we might have some more.
إن كنا ما زلنا جائعين, فيمكن أن نأكل قطعة أخرى.
If you eat too much, though,
ولكن إن أكلت كثيراً,
you just feel gross.
ستشعر بأنك ممتلئ وشره.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what if we could take this pizza model
لذا لما لا نأخذ نموذج البيتزا هذا
and overlay it on top of sexuality education?
ونستعمله في التثقيف الجنسي ؟
A lot of sexuality education that happens today
معظم التثقيف الجنسي الحاصل اليوم
is so influenced by the baseball model,
متأثّر بشكل كبير بنموذج البيسبول,
and it sets up education that can't help
والذي يخلق تثقيفاً لن يساهم إلا
but produce unhealthy sexuality in young people.
بإنتاج ثقافة جنسية غير سليمة عند الأطفال.
And those young people become older people.
وهؤلاء الأطفال سوف يكبرون.
But if we could create sexuality education
ولكن إن استطعنا خلق نظام تعليم جنسي
that was more like pizza,
يشبه البيتزا,
we could create education that invites people
سوف نستطيع خلق ثقافة تدعو العالم
to think about their own desires,
لأن يفكروا بملذاتهم الخاصة,
to make deliberate decisions about what they want,
وأن يقوموا بتحديد مالذي يريدونه بتأنّ,
to talk about it with their partners,
أن يتكلموا عنه مع شركائهم,
and to ultimately look for
وأن يبحثوا في النهاية
not some external outcome
ليس عن نتيجة خارجية
but for what feels satisfying,
وإنما عن ما يُشعر بالرضى,
and we get to decide that.
ونستحق أن نقرر هذا لأنفسنا.
You may have noticed
لابدّ أنك لاحظت
in the baseball and pizza comparison,
في نموذج مقارنة البيسبول والبيتزا,
under the baseball, it's all commands.
تحت البيسبول يوجد أوامر فقط.
They're all exclamation points.
إنها جميعها علامات تعجب.
But under the pizza model, they're questions.
ولكن تحت البيتزا , يوجد أسئلة .
And who gets to answer those questions?
ومن سيجاوب على هذه الأسئلة ؟
You do. I do.
أنت, انا .
So remember, when we're thinking about
لذا تذكر, عندما نفكر عن
sexuality education and sexual activity,
الثقافة الجنسية والنشاط الجنسي,
baseball, you're out.
بيسبول, خارجاً.
Pizza is the way to think about healthy,
والبيتزا هي الطريقة المثلى لعلاقة
satisfying sexual activity,
جنسية مُرضية وسليمة,
and good, comprehensive sexuality education.
و ثقافة جنسية أوسع.
Thank you very much for your time.
شكراً لكم جميعاً على وقتكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)